<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/second/</guid>
      <description>I. Vector What is a vector Linear combination Basis vector Span Linear independent What is a vector A vector with its coordinates can be understood as a guide on how to go from the origin (O) to its tail.
Basis vector (vector cơ sở) In the XY coordinate system, a vector pointing to the right with a length of 1 is called i-hat or the unit vector of the X-axis. Similarly, the vector pointing upwards with a length of 1 is called j-hat or the unit vector of the Y-axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metric regression</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/metric_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/metric_regression/</guid>
      <description>Metrics trong Machine Learning - Regression (P1) Trong phần này ta sẽ tìm hiểu về các metrics sau:
MSE - Mean Square Error RMSE - Root Mean Square Error R-Squared MAE - Mean Absolute Error và constant model của chúng
constant model: if we have to predict the same value for every object, what value is optimal to predict according to the chosen metric
có thể hiểu constant model là base model của chúng ta, nếu model của chúng ta predict có score dưới score của base model =&amp;gt; model chúng ta tệ hơn một model không học gì cả.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/neural_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/neural_network/</guid>
      <description>Xin chào mừng các bạn tới với serie Deep Learning đầu tiên của mình, mục tiêu của serie này là:
Hiểu rõ về thuật toán Neural Networks (Deep Learning) Tìm hiểu sơ lược qua để học AI bạn cần biết những gì Để có thể dễ dàng hiểu serie này bạn chỉ cần có kiến thức lập trình cơ bản, một chút toán hoặc nếu bạn tò mò AI là gì thì vẫn có thể đọc vì trong quá trình viết mình sẽ cung cấp những kiến thức cần thiết để bạn tìm hiểu thêm nếu hứng thú.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/python_optimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/python_optimize/</guid>
      <description>I. Complexity things
string.split() == O(n) : simple foward to look for an &amp;ldquo;white space&amp;rdquo; list.copy() == O(n) : simple foward and copy each element II. String things
Don&amp;rsquo;t ever += string, cuz it copy old string and create new string with suffiencent memory -&amp;gt; Use list append instead III. Python List Knowledge
Dynamic Array Array of pointers IV. Coding Style Optimize
Dont use if (Variable == True) -&amp;gt; if Variable </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNN</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/rnn/</guid>
      <description>I. RNN là gì? Đầu tiên mình xin giới thiệu 1 số ứng dụng của Sequence Model (RNN)
RNN là một biến thể của Neural Networks được sử dụng thường xuyên ở trong NLP (Natural language processing)
Ở một mạng Neural thông thường, các input được xử lý thông qua các layers và chúng ta có output, trong trường hợp này những input liên tiếp nhau được xem như không phụ thuộc vào nhau (independent)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias variance</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/bias_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 14:51:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/bias_variance/</guid>
      <description>Bias ? Variance ?
By looking at training error and valid error, we can diagnose what is the problem with our model
At first column, Train-error perform well, but Dev set not generalize well =&amp;gt; High Variance (Overfit) At second column, train-error did not well nor Dev set =&amp;gt; High bias (Underfit) At third column, High bias because not doing well on training set and High variance because even not doing well on trainset but dev set is even worse Final column, low bias low variance =&amp;gt; we want this Ilustration of all those things </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explain math</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/expain_math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 14:51:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/expain_math/</guid>
      <description>I have been started late, back to highschool all I did was just crunching all tons of numbers without understand it despite the fact that i&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at doing it. But since then, and from now on. Theres something different in my thought. I dont want to do thing that i don&amp;rsquo;t understand. I always crave for at least an intuition about hows it work. When started doing Machine Learning problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 14:51:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>architecture -&amp;gt; durability, utility, beauty
clean -&amp;gt; for each component, if you know where it is, what it is, why it is in the system
picture of clean architecture
RULE: only the layer that can see itself</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
