<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>let him cook</title>
    <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on let him cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 15:15:16 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is SimCSE?</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/nlp/simcse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/nlp/simcse/</guid>
      <description>Q: how does they know which one is posstiive or negative in unspervised task SimCSE
A: Suppose we have two sentences, &amp;ldquo;The cat sat on the mat&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The dog chased the ball.&amp;rdquo; The SimCSE algorithm first encodes these sentences into vectors using a pre-trained transformer-based language model like BERT. These sentence embeddings are then used to compute the similarity score between them. In SimCSE, the similarity score is calculated using the cosine similarity metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize CockroachDB using Index</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/db/indexes-cockroachdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/db/indexes-cockroachdb/</guid>
      <description>Indexes How do indexes works When you create an index, CockroachDB &amp;ldquo;indexes&amp;rdquo; the columns you specify, which creates a copy of the columns and then sorts their values (without sorting the values in the table itself).
After a column is indexed, SQL can easily filter its values using the index instead of scanning each row one-by-one.
Creation Primary key -&amp;gt; auto index
Secondary index -&amp;gt; find another column
Performance Trade-off between read and write, read faster but write longer because we have to write the data to the index column as well</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful metrics for Regression problems</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ml/metric_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ml/metric_regression/</guid>
      <description>Metrics trong Machine Learning - Regression (P1) Trong phần này ta sẽ tìm hiểu về các metrics sau:
MSE - Mean Square Error RMSE - Root Mean Square Error R-Squared MAE - Mean Absolute Error và constant model của chúng
constant model: if we have to predict the same value for every object, what value is optimal to predict according to the chosen metric
có thể hiểu constant model là base model của chúng ta, nếu model của chúng ta predict có score dưới score của base model =&amp;gt; model chúng ta tệ hơn một model không học gì cả.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias and Variance in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ml/bias_variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ml/bias_variance/</guid>
      <description>By looking at training error and valid error, we can diagnose what is the problem with our model
At first column, Train-error perform well, but Dev set not generalize well =&amp;gt; High Variance (Overfit) At second column, train-error did not well nor Dev set =&amp;gt; High bias (Underfit) At third column, High bias because not doing well on training set and High variance because even not doing well on trainset but dev set is even worse Final column, low bias low variance =&amp;gt; we want this Ilustrations </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Recurrent Neural Network?</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/nlp/rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/nlp/rnn/</guid>
      <description>I. RNN là gì? Đầu tiên mình xin giới thiệu 1 số ứng dụng của Sequence Model (RNN)
RNN là một biến thể của Neural Networks được sử dụng thường xuyên ở trong NLP (Natural language processing)
Ở một mạng Neural thông thường, các input được xử lý thông qua các layers và chúng ta có output, trong trường hợp này những input liên tiếp nhau được xem như không phụ thuộc vào nhau (independent)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Neural Network?</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ai/neural_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/ai/neural_network/</guid>
      <description>Xin chào mừng các bạn tới với serie Deep Learning đầu tiên của mình, mục tiêu của serie này là:
Hiểu rõ về thuật toán Neural Networks (Deep Learning) Tìm hiểu sơ lược qua để học AI bạn cần biết những gì Để có thể dễ dàng hiểu serie này bạn chỉ cần có kiến thức lập trình cơ bản, một chút toán hoặc nếu bạn tò mò AI là gì thì vẫn có thể đọc vì trong quá trình viết mình sẽ cung cấp những kiến thức cần thiết để bạn tìm hiểu thêm nếu hứng thú.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/math/basic_algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 15:15:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewNgo-ini.github.io/posts/math/basic_algebra/</guid>
      <description>I. Vector What is a vector Linear combination Basis vector Span Linear independent What is a vector A vector with its coordinates can be understood as a guide on how to go from the origin (O) to its tail.
Basis vector (vector cơ sở) In the XY coordinate system, a vector pointing to the right with a length of 1 is called i-hat or the unit vector of the X-axis. Similarly, the vector pointing upwards with a length of 1 is called j-hat or the unit vector of the Y-axis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
